We're in the process of hooking up the p trap for under the sink and I just want to remind you that the p trap acts as a gas break.
The water from the sink will always stay in at about this level and that keeps the gases coming back from the sewer, to come up through the sink drain.
And as long as there is water in here, that's where the gas is stopped, is right there.
So we're going to fit it into the trap adapter and we had to purchase an extra extension here, because right here is the top of my p trap and here's the bottom of the drain coming out of the sink.
So we bought this extension piece to make up the difference here.
So, let me see if I can get it in position here.
Nut goes on first and then we have a plastic compression ring, which as the nut comes down, it will compress against this pipe here, and around this flange right here and that will keep it from leaking.
So put the nut on.
Most of these fittings can just be hand tightened.
Ok, now our drain is hooked up.
Our supply lines are hooked up.
Our sink top has been glued to the top of the vanity.
We have our faucet in place.
We're ready for business.
Oh, I now have the scutchens , this is called a scutchen.
I think it's French.
Anyways, what it is designed to do, is to go around the hole in the drywall so that bugs and air and other things don't come through, and it kind of leaves it nice and pretty.
Now, what we do is where I have a mounted, then we can just take a screw and put through each hole and that holds it in place.
The only thing we have left to do here is to put our floor board in.